Bryan Braunstein

Software Engineer

Software engineer with a user-centered approach to coding and collaborating stemming from a service background. I help teams level up with innovation and communication. Driven to make an impact by building software that brings people closer to their goals, expertly, and on time. Proficient in JavaScript and its associated libraries.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive Program August 2020 - November 2020

12-week, 500+ hour full-time training program focused in Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Django, Bootstrap, Algorithms, etc.

Developed a portfolio of projects including:

PROJECTS

Tic Tac Toe — Link - GitHub

Addressed authentication and security concerns with Passport.JS, JWT tokens, and the Bcrypt library. Constructed API following RESTful standards, deploying the tool in a CICD pipeline through Travis and Heroku.

Crwn-Clothing — Link - GitHub

Store written in React using hooks, unidirectional data flow via Redux, GraphQL, Stripe payments, and Firebase. I kept code concise and readable, making structural decisions that would increase future scalability.

Once in a Lifetime — Link - GitHub

React, Node, MongoDB and an Express API Bucket List App leveraging RESTful routes and Axios. I acted as the Quality Assurance Lead and managed all developmental features, such as, pagination, and a 3rd party Unsplash API.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Fulfillment Associate Target | Torrington, Connecticut | August 2019 - January 2020

Collaborated with team members to effectively manage a high volume of 800 - 1200 orders daily in a fast-paced environment.

Server Bachi's | Torrington, Connecticut | April 2019 - July 2019

Increased sales to 5% higher than company average.

Server Denny's | West Haven, Connecticut & Amity, Connecticut | October 2017 - July 2018

Engaged in 200+ customer interactions weekly while maintaining service & customer retention.

Torrington, Connecticut (203) 257-5292

braunsteinbryan@gmail.com Portfolio LinkedIn GitHub Twitter

Tech Skills

Languages & Frameworks:

JavaScript, ES6, React, Mongoose, jQuery, Node.js, Express, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, Pug, Python, Django, Jest

Management & Deployment:

Git, GitHub, Heroku, NPM, Webpack, Babel

Databases:

SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, MongoDB, AWS

Methodologies:

Object Oriented
Programming,Test-Driven
Development,
Semantic HTML,
Responsive Design,
Authentication, User
Stories, ERDs,
Wireframing, Agile
Development/Scrum

Soft Skills

Communication, Collaboration, Marketing, Customer Service, Sales, Management, Reliable, Motivational, Teammate

Education

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive 08/2020 - 11/2020

> Gateway Community College Completed coursework in computer science 09/2018 - 01/2019